Hello everyone so welcome to my
demo cloud portfolio
Platform so here I would like to
explain a little bit about my
Project so I build this project
around
Some important tools and
services that I believe that are
Essential for real environment
like
Security automation and high availability
So as we can see here on the
diagram everything starts here
In
GitHub repository so I'll say
this is the source of truth for
The application so where we can
find the
Infrastructure that's good and then
we have GitHub Actions
Workflow so why I chose
GitHub Actions workflow I push a
Change to main
branch GitHub Actions
Automatically starts deployment
Pipeline so is
Gives a consistent and
repeatable process which is very
Good for an engineer because
everything is automated with
GitHub Actions workflow and the
deployment is the same every
Time there is less room for a
human
Error and then we have here
OIDC so there is no static key
For this particular
Platform and I took this
decision
This probably one of the most
important security decision that
I made for this
Architecture why because GitHub Actions always needs permission to
Deploy into google cloud a
nd a common approach would be to
Create a service account key and
store that key as a
Secret but this doesn't follow
best
Practices instead of
that I decided to use a workload
identity
Federation as we can see
here why I decide to to choose
The workflow identity
Federation because uh as
I said GitHub and
Google cloud they need to
establish a trust so GitHub can
Deploy into uh
google cloud and the workflow
Receives a short-lived
credential when it needs to
Deploy so with OIDC there is no
static key
So there's no permanent cloud key sitting in GitHub waiting
To be legal or
Forgotten so the security
perspective it's much stronger
With
OIDC and then here we have the
IAM service
Account so why is important to
have a IAM service
Account having a service
IAM account it's so important
Because it follows the principle of least
privilege — it has only the
permission required to deploy
The
Website so it's not an
administrator account and it
Does not have unnecessary access
to the rest of the
Environment so then we follow
the deploy here so it deploys to
Firebase
Hosting and the the reason
I chose this service is
Simple I don't want
The availability of the static
website to depend on a single
Server that I have to manage
Myself and Firebase gives it to
me because everything is
Completely automated and is a
serverless
Service so Firebase uses
google's global delivery
Infrastructure so the content
also is completely
Distributed close to
User and https is handled
automatically for a portfolio
And my static web
application this gives me high
availability and global delivery
which is everything that I need
For this platform and for my
website so in the next video
I'll be explaining a little bit
more about cloud dns and
Caa record thank you very much
for watching this video